# Emilio Campos Jr.

Chicago, IL | (815) 543-8461 | ecampos.jr54@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

As a former lawyer, I managed over 60 cases at once, collaborated with multiple teams, and ensured compliance with court procedures. I analyzed about 400 pages of detailed information per case and researched case law to resolve issues. I applied these skills to develop applications in my software engineering boot camp: I collaborated with teams, analyzed numerous problems, and researched to debug any issues. These experiences have made me a highly effective software engineer.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

JavaScript | MongoDB | Express | React | Node | SQL | NoSQL | PostgreSQL | HTML | CSS | Python | Flask | Tailwind

#### TECHNICAL PROJECTS

## Video Game Library | Code | App

- Designed a MERN-stack application with two libraries of games, including one for user customization
- Connected this SPA using a MongoDB database containing information regarding each game
- Built UI with React and Tailwind CSS for users to perform full CRUD functionality on each item
- Rendered video game data fetched by HTTP requests from the RAWG Video Games Database API
- Deployed app to Heroku using Git and managed Git repositories with GitHub

## GitRipped | Code | App

- React single page application that contains preset exercises and allows users to customize their own
- Built the backend, including the model, view, and controller layers to organize data for each exercise
- Connected the application to a third-party REST API to import exercises and render data
- Created the UI components to show both custom and API exercises
- Extensively engaged in pair programming, debugging and version control best practices

### Ollivanders | Code | App

- Utilized Node.js, Mongoose, Express and EJS
- Implemented 7 RESTful routes and full CRUD functionality to allow the user to view, edit and add custom wands
- Used the Models, Views and Controllers paradigm (MVC) to design and create templates for each product

#### Emilio's Blackjack | Code | App

- Applied CSS to HTML elements via extensive DOM manipulation
- Researched JavaScript loops and combined them with the push method to form the deck as an array
- Implemented various functions housed within multiple if and else if functions to deal cards randomly

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Staff Attorney I | Catholic Charities Legal Assistance

06/2021 - 04/2022

- Identified legal problems of over 100 clients and communicated their resolution options to them
- Communicated with multiple opposing counsels to reach optimal case resolution for clients

## Associate Attorney | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

01/2021 - 06/2021

- Collaborated with multiple teams to execute case plan based on court deadlines and procedures
- Developed detailed legal strategy based on analysis of incident, medical treatment, and trial costs

#### Law Clerk | Bryce Downey and Lenkov LLC

01/2020 - 06/2020 & 10/2020 - 01/2021

• Researched case law extensively and adapted findings to calculate damages and write court motions

#### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly   Software Engineering Certification	11/2022
University of Illinois College of Law   Juris Doctor	05/2020
<b>Lovola University Chicago</b>   Bachelor of Business Administration in Economics and Business Management	05/2013